## **Ethan Wollman**

EthanJWollman@gmail.com 215-850-9924 Philadelphia, PA - 19102



## **Business Analyst**

GitHub Portfolio LinkedIn

I am a business analyst skilled in Excel, Tableau, PowerPoint, SQL, and Python. I have spent the last six months specializing in data modeling and analytics, additionally I hold a bachelor's in economics with a background in real estate and nonprofit industries.

Skills: Excel, Tableau, Python, SQL, Statistical Analysis, html/CSS, MSOffice, GIS, Data cleaning & processing, statistical imagery

## **Recent Projects**

## **Operations Dashboard**

Description: Built a KPI dashboard for Mid/Senior level executives. The dashboard utilizes 14 different visualizations for analysis.

#### SQL Data in Python

Description: Executed SQL queries in python pertaining to film ratings in a database- returned breakdowns of key information.

#### Lariat Rental Corp. Growth Excel Model

Description: Created an interactive Excel model to determine long term profitability of a car rental business.

## **Experience**

## Center Stage Tickets

### Purchasing, Inventory Analyst

Remote/Bala Cynwyd, PA

January 2019 - April 2020

- Used historical data and current trends to build visualizations regarding the profitability of future events
- Managed over \$50,000 in event tickets for company, and managed pricing of this inventory
- Generated a 37.9% ROI (Average) for inventory purchased
- Interacted daily with Center Stage's historical data in Tableau, and built excel models to populate essential information

# National Philanthropic Trust Donor Relations Associate (Contract)

Jenkintown, PA

September 2019 – January 2020

- Tracked, escalated, and resolved calls, emails, fulfillment requests and issues through a Salesforce case management system
- Provided exceptional and efficient front-line service to inquiries from high net worth donors and financial advisors
- Contributed to the DAF Report which analyzes the donor advised fund industry and measures industry growth and changes

# Ironstone Real Estate Partners Property Management and Operations Intern

Philadelphia, PA

June 2018 – September 2020

- Assisted in the logistics and operations of a 130-unit apartment complex renovation
- Worked in Excel to model various income streams, as well as organize data and present this information
- Managed Yardi data and portal information and integrated new data into the system

Additional Internships: Bureau of Labor Statistics, Apex K.K (Tokyo, Japan), National Philanthropic Trust

## **Education**

# THINKFUL Data Analytics Program

Graduation Date: June 2020

- Used a variety of mediums (SQL, Python, Tableau, Excel) to deliver business value from data sets. Discovered key material and presented this information to my peers and mentors.
- Learned the nuts and bolts of data science and how to affectively create and share effective deliverables
- Practical mastery of Excel, PowerPoint, PostgreSQL/ MySQL, Tableau, and Python for data analysis.

### **Temple University**

Bachelors, Economics Graduation Date: May 2019

GPA: 3.41

- Intermediate Macro/Micro Principles, Behavioral Economics, Statistics, Econometrics, Digital Mapping
- Senior Thesis: "What Are the Odds, A Comprehensive Look into the World of Sports Wagering"